<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-28T12:51:04+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Australian Government goes all in on e-invoicing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200929" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Australian Government goes all in on e-invoicing" /><published>2020-09-28T12:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-28T12:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/All-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200929">&lt;p&gt;As e-invoicing specialists, Capability Wise has been closely watching the progress of the joint Australian and New Zealand Government’s Peppol e-invoicing initiative.  The iniative was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pm.gov.au/media/joint-statement-prime-ministers-rt-hon-jacinda-ardern-and-hon-scott-morrison-mp&quot;&gt;originally announced&lt;/a&gt; by the respective Prime Ministers back in February 2019, the initiative is expected to save an estimated $30 billion in reduced transaction costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Budget 2021 announcements&lt;/a&gt;, the Australian government has declared that it is going all in on e-invoicing.  &lt;strong&gt;Today the government announced a mandate for all Commonwealth, State, Territory and Local Governments to support e-invoicing by [DATE X].&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a significant move that is intended to bolster Australia’s post-COVID economic recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how exactly does e-invoicing assist economic recovery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suppliers to Australian Government Agencies will be able to access favourable payment terms when they e-invoice a government customer.  Enabled Government agencies will pay supplier valid e-invoices within 5 business days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Australian e-invoicing network will soon be able to support digital e-invoice response messages.  This will allow business to see the processing status of their e-invoices, saving time and more spent on follow up phone calls.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E-invoices cost less to process than their paper and PDF equivalents – reducing government operating costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a government agency interested in adopting e-invoicing or a supplier to government, Capability Wise can assist you to take the first steps on your e-invoicing journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us today for more information: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:einvoicing@capabilitywise.com.au&quot;&gt;einvoicing@capabilitywise.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><category term="government" /><category term="mandate" /><summary type="html">As part of the Budget 2021 announcements, the Australian government has declared that it is going all in on e-invoicing. Announcing an e-invoicing mandate that applies to all Commonwealth, State and Local government agencies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting started with electronic invoicing (e-invoicing)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200928-01" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting started with electronic invoicing (e-invoicing)" /><published>2020-09-28T12:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-28T12:14:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/Getting-Started</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200928-01">&lt;p&gt;As e-invoicing specialists, the first question we often get asked &lt;strong&gt;“where do I start?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 18 commercial e-invoicing Access Points accredited by the ATO in the last 12 months, &lt;strong&gt;“shouldn’t we just pick one and let them sort it out?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we all truly know the answer to that question is… NO.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintaining the operational integrity of your Accounts Payable and Accounts Receivable processes is critical to the operation of your organisation.  We have all see the horror stories of technology projects gone wrong.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itnews.com.au/news/qld-healths-sap-implementation-led-to-540m-in-invoices-paid-late-553919&quot;&gt;Queensland Health’s recent experience&lt;/a&gt;, and resulting $540m in late payments, highlights the need for structured, business-led approach to AR/AP transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Capability Wise we are both experts in e-invoicing technology standards and in digital transformation.  This combination allows us to guide you through the process of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing your AR/AP transformation and preparing a business case for executive endorsement,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selecting the right e-invoicing Access Point provider to meet your business requirements,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparing your buyer and supplier networks for transition and on-boarding, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preparing your AR/AP teams for the changing business processes and automation opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you considering where to start on your e-invoicing journey, then contact us today for a confidential chat.  &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:einvoicing@capabilitywise.com.au&quot;&gt;einvoicing@capabilitywise.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><category term="government" /><summary type="html">We often get asked by a government and corporate customers, 'Where do I start with e-invoicing..?', 'When do I need to be ready for e-invoicing..?', or 'What do I tell me suppliers..?'</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Practices: The importance of supplier onboarding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200828" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Practices: The importance of supplier onboarding" /><published>2020-08-31T11:39:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T11:39:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/SupplierOnboarding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200828">&lt;p&gt;The first step in developing a lasting relationship with your suppliers is through efficient onboarding. A supplier who experiences a professional introduction to your company is left confident in other aspects of the business, including what is for them, the most important (and often-painful) process of being paid in full and on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the buyer, the onboarding process offers a level of protection through establishing a partnership with the new vendor - developing a profile in their supplier database, confirming payment terms and ensuring the organisation meets its regulatory and ethical requirements.  Depending on the size of the business and the scope of works, a more in-depth onboarding process can be employed to further vet suppliers, evaluating any risks that may impact on your bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When onboarding any new vendor, buyers should use Australian Business Register resource &lt;a href=&quot;https://abr.business.gov.au/&quot;&gt;ABN Lookup&lt;/a&gt; to ensure the legitimacy of the company, confirming details such as the ABN and legal name, as well as checking the taxation (or GST) to ensure the correct payment amount has been requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good practice for a buyer to confirm available payment means any time they are establishing ongoing supply arrangements. On top of this, in order to ensure prompt payment for suppliers, especially those providing longer term arrangements, buyers should collect relevant information in advance. If the payment is being made via direct deposit, details required include the supplier’s account name, BSB and account number.  Businesses should also consider utilising &lt;a href=&quot;https://payid.com.au/&quot;&gt;PayID&lt;/a&gt; as a viable payment option, allowing a supplier to nominate their ABN as their PayID.  This method of payment is particularly useful for small businesses as it provides an additional layer of authentication, avoiding one of the more common types of invoice fraud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that buyers undertake due diligence in relation to supply chain risks when considering entering strategic supplier relationships. Buyers across Australia and the world have learnt firsthand the risks associated with relying on cross border and import supply in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic. For the first time (but arguably not the last) the nation was sent into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mumbrella.com.au/woolworths-takes-out-full-page-ads-to-explain-toilet-paper-shortage-and-new-covid-19-safety-measures-623770&quot;&gt;tailspin over toilet paper&lt;/a&gt;, providing an exceptional metaphor to explain the perils of largely importing a nation’s supply of essential items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wholistic vendor onboarding process alleviates risks associated with the viability of a vendor, evaluating whether an organisation is financially and operationally stable, providing the added security of evidence of insurance and appropriate certifications such as food safety compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robust processes around vendor onboarding provide safeguards for both the buyer and the supplier.  To ensure a company is getting the most out of vendor onboarding, management should consider an independent assessment of current practices, and depending on scale may benefit from implementing supplier self-service capabilities to maintain accurate information.&lt;br /&gt;
Remember, first impressions last, so invest some time and potentially money in developing rigorous vendor onboarding processes today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="Best Practices" /><category term="Supplier Management" /><category term="Onboarding" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><summary type="html">First Impressions Last! The first step in developing a lasting relationship with your suppliers is through efficient onboarding. A supplier who experiences a professional introduction to your company is left confident in...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Procurement: Establishing a Whole of Government Panel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/6" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Procurement: Establishing a Whole of Government Panel" /><published>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/procurement-wog-panel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/6">&lt;h3 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenges&quot;&gt;The Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-capability-wise-helped&quot;&gt;How Capability Wise Helped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TBA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Role]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Government" /><category term="Procurement" /><summary type="html">A Case Study on the successful development of a Whole of Government Panel Arrangement.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Global Thought Leadership and Technology Insights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Global Thought Leadership and Technology Insights" /><published>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/thought-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/1">&lt;h3 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Australian Taxation Office (ATO) is a global leader in the provision of integrated
government systems and services to business and tax practitioner communities. Over
one billion system-to-system transactions will flow between financial management
software and the ATO’s systems this financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past ten years the number of digital transactions has steadily increased from a
few hundred thousand to current levels. In parallel the ATO has extended the breadth
and depth of its services to support over 100 different services and has been integrated
with over 500 software products. This success has not been without it challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise was engaged by the ATO to map out its next evolution, chart the
path already travelled and the key lessons learned. We were selected for this engagement
due to our extensive expertise in API technologies, knowledge of the ATO’s digital
supply chain, and hands on involvement across much of the ATO’s ten year digital
service journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ATO recognised the potential of our work products beyond its own boundaries and
we collaborated to transform them into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/tax/forum-on-tax-administration/publications-and-products/unlocking-the-digital-economy-guide-to
-implementing-application-programming-interfaces-in-government.htm&quot;&gt;guidance paper&lt;/a&gt; for the Organisation for
Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) Forum on Tax Administration and
tabled at the 12th FTA Plenary in Santiago, Chile on the 26th March 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenges&quot;&gt;The Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology evolves quickly and government organisations are struggling to keep pace
with innovation on a global level. The OECD approached the ATO to collect insights on the
use of APIs by its member countries and to apply these insights to produce practical
guidance to support member countries in the implementation of effective API strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of sustained investment in system-to-system technologies the ATO was at a
cross-road. With newly popularised technology and changing stakeholder expectations
it needed assistance to establish a practical path forward that built upon its own successful
experience and learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-capability-wise-helped&quot;&gt;How Capability Wise Helped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet its internal future strategy needs and to fulfil the OECD’s request the ATO sought specialist API expertise from Capability Wise. Our expert consultants provided the following capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Thought Leadership&lt;/strong&gt; – to translate global technology trends into actionable insights and strategies.
Interpretation of the global and domestic landscape – including documentation of several international case studies, each with diverse circumstances and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application of API Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt; – to describe the decision process required to develop resilient, secure API Architectures with due consideration of business models and developer empathy to rapid time to market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Delivery Experience&lt;/strong&gt; – to describe the critical business and technology capabilities required for a successful API program.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capability Maturity Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – to understand the diverse motivations, skill levels and expertise of the existing API delivery teams.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Security Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – to identify potential risk areas and co-design/develop mitigations with industry stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whitepaper Documentation Skills&lt;/strong&gt; – to document insights, fundings and recommencations in a transparent and inclusive manner.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our Managing Director Matt Lewis was asked to document the ATO’s lessons learned. This was due in large part to his pivotal role in the establishing the ATO’s current API and Web Service Capabilities, and it Digital Service Provider supply chain security model for several of its flagship platforms and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise worked with the ATO to create a fully referenced whitepaper, providing thought leadership and practical assistance to tax administrations, and other parts of government, which are seeking to implement or further develop their API Strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is entitled: &lt;em&gt;“Unlocking the Digital Economy - A guide to Implementing Application Programming Interfaces in Government”&lt;/em&gt; and is available via the OECD website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/tax/forum-on-tax-administration/publications-and-products/unlocking-the-digital-economy-guide-to
-implementing-application-programming-interfaces-in-government.htm&quot;&gt;Click to read.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Capability Wise Pty Ltd provided the ATO with support and technical guidance
in developing the paper ‘Unlocking the Digital Economy – A guide to Implementing
Application Programming Interfaces in Government’.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“This paper was subsequently published by the Organisation for Economic
Co-operation and Development (OECD) in 2019.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“In particular we’d like to acknowledge the efforts of Matt Lewis. His contribution
was knowledgeable, timely and insightful.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Dardo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chief Digital Officer - Australian Taxation Office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Government" /><category term="OECD" /><summary type="html">A Case Study on the successful development of technology guidance for OECD member countries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Practices: Invoice Verification &amp;amp; Matching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Practices: Invoice Verification &amp;amp; Matching" /><published>2020-08-21T11:39:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:39:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/ThreeWayMatching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-2">&lt;p&gt;As your company grows, so too does your responsibility to ensure the integrity of your business practices.  When it comes to paying accounts, sloppy processes can impact on your bottom line – increasing your risk of errors and exposure to invoice fraud, eroding the trust of reliable suppliers and costing your business time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing an invoice verification process is the most reliable way to guarantee the robustness of your accounts payable (AP) procedures. Widely accepted in the finance industry as best practice, businesses are encouraged to use a method of either two-, three- or four-way matching, where, depending on needs, scale and risk profile, businesses can cross-reference a variety of details to ensure accuracy. If any issues are detected during the matching process, payment of the invoice will be withheld pending validation, ensuring that everyone gets what they should in terms of product and payment, and, equally as important, providing a safeguard against someone receiving something they shouldn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three-way matching involves cross referencing the details on purchase orders, receiving notes and invoices - comparing company name, type and quantity of goods or services requested and supplied, agreed price, payment terms, and purchase order number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this, it is good practice to extend checks on invoices to include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cross checking payment account details against vendor records;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maintaining a database of invoices received in order to detect duplicate submissions; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;validating invoice calculations including totals and tax amounts, ensuring that the invoice meets the minimum &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ato.gov.au/Business/GST/Tax-invoices/&quot;&gt;content requirements&lt;/a&gt; as outlined by the Australian Tax Office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many businesses persist with managing this process manually. While this is acceptable, there are some obvious issues with continuing to handle the AP aspects of business this way. First and foremost, human error is real. People make mistakes – staff take leave, have lapses in concentration, some struggle with following detailed procedures.  As a business continues to grow, manual handling increases along with workloads and invoice payment times, impacting on staff satisfaction and relationships with suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/20200815-2-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to overcome the issues associated with a manual validation system is to transition toward a digital AP process, making use of some of the many automated solutions available to the industry.  Options vary depending on the needs of each business. Small businesses should consider adopting modern accounting software, for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://quickbooks.intuit.com/au/&quot;&gt;Intuit QuickBooks Online&lt;/a&gt;, e-invoicing and related automation tools to streamline their AP process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medium to large businesses may benefit from utilising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;e-invoicing to improve data quality;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;robotic process automation (RPA) to increase efficiency of tedious and repetitive tasks; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;artificial intelligence (AI) to identify risk patterns and opportunities to maximise supply chain benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the rapid rate of technology development today, some businesses are still resistant to adopting digital processes.  Considering the many benefits that come with automating AP processes like three-way matching - saving money, improving efficiency, minimising risks, and strengthening relationships - there has never been a better time to make the transition!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="Best Practices" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><summary type="html">When it comes to paying accounts, sloppy processes can impact on your bottom line – increasing your risk of errors and exposure to invoice fraud, eroding the trust of reliable suppliers and costing your business time and money...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">eCommerce Platform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="eCommerce Platform" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/ecommerce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/5"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="APIs" /><category term="eCommerce" /><summary type="html">Case Study 1...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whole of Sector Data Management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whole of Sector Data Management" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/industry-architecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/3"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Data" /><summary type="html">Case Study 1...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Large Scale Data Collection and Validation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Large Scale Data Collection and Validation" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/large-scale-data-collection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/4"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Data" /><summary type="html">Case Study 1...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital transformation born out of COVID-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200824" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital transformation born out of COVID-19" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/DigitalTransformation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200824">&lt;p&gt;From small business to large enterprise and government agencies, so many businesses have felt the impact of the global pandemic. The crisis has forced businesses to make changes to their service offering that they were not prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2020, Capability Wise was engaged by a state-wide wholesale food distributor to support the business rapidly pivot to meet the needs of the market as a result of COVID-19 restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distributor is well established, using traditional business to business sales methods and channels. Our client had been wanting to introduce a compatible digital solution into their service offering for some time, however had been experiencing a number of barriers to entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first met with our client, they had minimal awareness of the solutions that were available to them. Their awareness was limited to information received from vendors who were promoting off the shelf products that had been developed for the food service industry but weren’t meeting the specific needs of our client. These solutions were costly, technically complex and required a time investment that our client just didn’t have. After a brief discussion, we were able to demonstrate solutions that would be fit for purpose, able to be tailored to the customer’s needs and also evolve as the business and its customers become more comfortable with the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time was of the essence when Capability Wise was engaged, as trading restrictions had been announced and it was thought that they could become harsher, impacting our client’s ability to continue to operate. Many of their customers had already been impacted by the restrictions, so an alternative service offering was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition to a digital service offering had a few initial challenges to work through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment in digital solutions had historically been limited,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client had outdated online presence and limited social media presence,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client did not have dedicated IT support, so the solution needed to be tailored for non-technical users,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As part of the pivot, the client wanted to expand their services to the new consumer market segments and offer home delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/business-change.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the client had the home delivery solution sorted, being able to redirect existing delivery capacity to support home delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise a undertook review of the current product offering and worked with the client to create a refined product offering suitable for the target market segments. Corporate and industry knowledge was key in this activity and the client was instrumental in building the product offerings to address the new market segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise established an eCommerce solution over the course of 48 hours. Normally, this kind of delivery would involve weeks of current process review, analysis, planning, training and implementation. As our client was under immense pressure to have a solution available to the public in a short timeframe, the team at Capability Wise worked around the clock to ensure that the client had a market ready product by the deadline. The delivery of an engaging eCommerce solution would not have been possible without client participation in the development and testing of the solution, skills and expertise contributed by Capability Wise paired with familiarity of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel to the build of the new online service, Capability Wise also launched a new social media presence that was utilised over the course of the initial 48 hours to commence a marketing campaign promoting the new service offering. The audience was built organically through existing customer networks and leveraged off the fact that home delivery being offered by our client was filling a market gap left by the suspension of large supermarket home delivery services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/supermarket.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online service continues to evolve, our client experiencing benefits that were largely unexpected. Their suppliers are approaching them to partner in cross promotional activities,  unveiling a new revenue stream that wasn’t attainable before, a by-product of these promotional activities has seen the relationship with their suppliers growing stronger and opening more opportunities for business growth in previously unexplored ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of COVID-19 has been devastating to millions of people, however, those who have embraced digital transformation and pivoted in some manner have been able to stay in business and in some cases, realise opportunities that may not have happened without the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="technology" /><category term="Business Transformation" /><category term="Digital Transformation" /><category term="COVID-19 Response" /><category term="e-commerce" /><summary type="html">From small business to large enterprise and government agencies, so many businesses have felt the impact of the global pandemic. The crisis has forced businesses to make changes to their service offering...</summary></entry></feed>