<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-30T11:53:08+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Global Thought Leadership and Technology Insights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Global Thought Leadership and Technology Insights" /><published>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-28T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/thought-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/1">&lt;h3 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Australian Taxation Office (ATO) is a global leader in the provision of integrated
government systems and services to business and tax practitioner communities. Over
one billion system-to-system transactions will flow between financial management
software and the ATO’s systems this financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past ten years the number of digital transactions has steadily increased from a
few hundred thousand to current levels. In parallel the ATO has extended the breadth
and depth of its services to support over 100 different services and has been integrated
with over 500 software products. This success has not been without it challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise was engaged by the ATO to map out its next evolution, chart the
path already travelled and the key lessons learned. We were selected for this engagement
due to our extensive expertise in API technologies, knowledge of the ATO’s digital
supply chain, and hands on involvement across much of the ATO’s ten year digital
service journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ATO recognised the potential of our work products beyond its own boundaries and
we collaborated to transform them into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/tax/forum-on-tax-administration/publications-and-products/unlocking-the-digital-economy-guide-to
-implementing-application-programming-interfaces-in-government.htm&quot;&gt;guidance paper&lt;/a&gt; for the Organisation for
Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) Forum on Tax Administration and
tabled at the 12th FTA Plenary in Santiago, Chile on the 26th March 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenges&quot;&gt;The Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology evolves quickly and government organisations are struggling to keep pace
with innovation on a global level. The OECD approached the ATO to collect insights on the
use of APIs by its member countries and to apply these insights to produce practical
guidance to support member countries in the implementation of effective API strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of sustained investment in system-to-system technologies the ATO was at a
cross-road. With newly popularised technology and changing stakeholder expectations
it needed assistance to establish a practical path forward that built upon its own successful
experience and learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-capability-wise-helped&quot;&gt;How Capability Wise Helped&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet its internal future strategy needs and to fulfil the OECD’s request the ATO sought specialist API expertise from Capability Wise. Our expert consultants provided the following capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Thought Leadership&lt;/strong&gt; – to translate global technology trends into actionable insights and strategies.
Interpretation of the global and domestic landscape – including documentation of several international case studies, each with diverse circumstances and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application of API Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt; – to describe the decision process required to develop resilient, secure API Architectures with due consideration of business models and developer empathy to rapid time to market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Delivery Experience&lt;/strong&gt; – to describe the critical business and technology capabilities required for a successful API program.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capability Maturity Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – to understand the diverse motivations, skill levels and expertise of the existing API delivery teams.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Security Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – to identify potential risk areas and co-design/develop mitigations with industry stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whitepaper Documentation Skills&lt;/strong&gt; – to document insights, fundings and recommencations in a transparent and inclusive manner.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our Managing Director Matt Lewis was asked to document the ATO’s lessons learned. This was due in large part to his pivotal role in the establishing the ATO’s current API and Web Service Capabilities, and it Digital Service Provider supply chain security model for several of its flagship platforms and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise worked with the ATO to create a fully referenced whitepaper, providing thought leadership and practical assistance to tax administrations, and other parts of government, which are seeking to implement or further develop their API Strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is entitled: &lt;em&gt;“Unlocking the Digital Economy - A guide to Implementing Application Programming Interfaces in Government”&lt;/em&gt; and is available via the OECD website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/tax/forum-on-tax-administration/publications-and-products/unlocking-the-digital-economy-guide-to
-implementing-application-programming-interfaces-in-government.htm&quot;&gt;Click to read.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Capability Wise Pty Ltd provided the ATO with support and technical guidance
in developing the paper ‘Unlocking the Digital Economy – A guide to Implementing
Application Programming Interfaces in Government’.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“This paper was subsequently published by the Organisation for Economic
Co-operation and Development (OECD) in 2019.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“In particular we’d like to acknowledge the efforts of Matt Lewis. His contribution
was knowledgeable, timely and insightful.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Dardo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chief Digital Officer - Australian Taxation Office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Government" /><category term="OECD" /><summary type="html">A Case Study on the successful development of technology guidance for OECD member countries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Practices: Invoice Verification &amp;amp; Matching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Practices: Invoice Verification &amp;amp; Matching" /><published>2020-08-21T11:39:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:39:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/ThreeWayMatching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-2">&lt;p&gt;As your company grows, so too does your responsibility to ensure the integrity of your business practices.  When it comes to paying accounts, sloppy processes can impact on your bottom line – increasing your risk of errors and exposure to invoice fraud, eroding the trust of reliable suppliers and costing your business time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing an invoice verification process is the most reliable way to guarantee the robustness of your accounts payable (AP) procedures. Widely accepted in the finance industry as best practice, businesses are encouraged to use a method of either two-, three- or four-way matching, where, depending on needs, scale and risk profile, businesses can cross-reference a variety of details to ensure accuracy. If any issues are detected during the matching process, payment of the invoice will be withheld pending validation, ensuring that everyone gets what they should in terms of product and payment, and, equally as important, providing a safeguard against someone receiving something they shouldn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three-way matching involves cross referencing the details on purchase orders, receiving notes and invoices - comparing company name, type and quantity of goods or services requested and supplied, agreed price, payment terms, and purchase order number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this, it is good practice to extend checks on invoices to include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cross checking payment account details against vendor records;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maintaining a database of invoices received in order to detect duplicate submissions; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;validating invoice calculations including totals and tax amounts, ensuring that the invoice meets the minimum &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ato.gov.au/Business/GST/Tax-invoices/&quot;&gt;content requirements&lt;/a&gt; as outlined by the Australian Tax Office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many businesses persist with managing this process manually. While this is acceptable, there are some obvious issues with continuing to handle the AP aspects of business this way. First and foremost, human error is real. People make mistakes – staff take leave, have lapses in concentration, some struggle with following detailed procedures.  As a business continues to grow, manual handling increases along with workloads and invoice payment times, impacting on staff satisfaction and relationships with suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/20200815-2-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to overcome the issues associated with a manual validation system is to transition toward a digital AP process, making use of some of the many automated solutions available to the industry.  Options vary depending on the needs of each business. Small businesses should consider adopting modern accounting software, for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://quickbooks.intuit.com/au/&quot;&gt;Intuit QuickBooks Online&lt;/a&gt;, e-invoicing and related automation tools to streamline their AP process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medium to large businesses may benefit from utilising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;e-invoicing to improve data quality;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;robotic process automation (RPA) to increase efficiency of tedious and repetitive tasks; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;artificial intelligence (AI) to identify risk patterns and opportunities to maximise supply chain benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the rapid rate of technology development today, some businesses are still resistant to adopting digital processes.  Considering the many benefits that come with automating AP processes like three-way matching - saving money, improving efficiency, minimising risks, and strengthening relationships - there has never been a better time to make the transition!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="Best Practices" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><summary type="html">When it comes to paying accounts, sloppy processes can impact on your bottom line – increasing your risk of errors and exposure to invoice fraud, eroding the trust of reliable suppliers and costing your business time and money...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital transformation born out of COVID-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200824" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital transformation born out of COVID-19" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/DigitalTransformation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200824">&lt;p&gt;From small business to large enterprise and government agencies, so many businesses have felt the impact of the global pandemic. The crisis has forced businesses to make changes to their service offering that they were not prepared for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2020, Capability Wise was engaged by a state-wide wholesale food distributor to support the business rapidly pivot to meet the needs of the market as a result of COVID-19 restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distributor is well established, using traditional business to business sales methods and channels. Our client had been wanting to introduce a compatible digital solution into their service offering for some time, however had been experiencing a number of barriers to entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first met with our client, they had minimal awareness of the solutions that were available to them. Their awareness was limited to information received from vendors who were promoting off the shelf products that had been developed for the food service industry but weren’t meeting the specific needs of our client. These solutions were costly, technically complex and required a time investment that our client just didn’t have. After a brief discussion, we were able to demonstrate solutions that would be fit for purpose, able to be tailored to the customer’s needs and also evolve as the business and its customers become more comfortable with the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time was of the essence when Capability Wise was engaged, as trading restrictions had been announced and it was thought that they could become harsher, impacting our client’s ability to continue to operate. Many of their customers had already been impacted by the restrictions, so an alternative service offering was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition to a digital service offering had a few initial challenges to work through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment in digital solutions had historically been limited,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client had outdated online presence and limited social media presence,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client did not have dedicated IT support, so the solution needed to be tailored for non-technical users,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As part of the pivot, the client wanted to expand their services to the new consumer market segments and offer home delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/business-change.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the client had the home delivery solution sorted, being able to redirect existing delivery capacity to support home delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise a undertook review of the current product offering and worked with the client to create a refined product offering suitable for the target market segments. Corporate and industry knowledge was key in this activity and the client was instrumental in building the product offerings to address the new market segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise established an eCommerce solution over the course of 48 hours. Normally, this kind of delivery would involve weeks of current process review, analysis, planning, training and implementation. As our client was under immense pressure to have a solution available to the public in a short timeframe, the team at Capability Wise worked around the clock to ensure that the client had a market ready product by the deadline. The delivery of an engaging eCommerce solution would not have been possible without client participation in the development and testing of the solution, skills and expertise contributed by Capability Wise paired with familiarity of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel to the build of the new online service, Capability Wise also launched a new social media presence that was utilised over the course of the initial 48 hours to commence a marketing campaign promoting the new service offering. The audience was built organically through existing customer networks and leveraged off the fact that home delivery being offered by our client was filling a market gap left by the suspension of large supermarket home delivery services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blogs/supermarket.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online service continues to evolve, our client experiencing benefits that were largely unexpected. Their suppliers are approaching them to partner in cross promotional activities,  unveiling a new revenue stream that wasn’t attainable before, a by-product of these promotional activities has seen the relationship with their suppliers growing stronger and opening more opportunities for business growth in previously unexplored ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The impact of COVID-19 has been devastating to millions of people, however, those who have embraced digital transformation and pivoted in some manner have been able to stay in business and in some cases, realise opportunities that may not have happened without the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="technology" /><category term="Business Transformation" /><category term="Digital Transformation" /><category term="COVID-19 Response" /><category term="e-commerce" /><summary type="html">From small business to large enterprise and government agencies, so many businesses have felt the impact of the global pandemic. The crisis has forced businesses to make changes to their service offering...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Industry Engagement for a large government agency</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Industry Engagement for a large government agency" /><published>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case-studies/industry-engagement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case-studies/2">&lt;h4 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the 2016-17 Federal Budget the Australian Government announced a study
into the feasibility of Electronic Invoicing (e-invoicing). The Australian Taxation Office
(ATO) was tasked with leading the operational elements of this study and established a
multi-stakeholder forum known as the Digital Business Council to further eInvoicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capability Wise was engaged by the ATO to undertake consultation with the technology
and business service industries in support of this initiative. Our team translated international
technology trends and complex technology challenges into clear, concise options
for consideration by the Council’s nominated representatives. The scope of consultation
spanned multiple working parties, including technology, governance, information
management and adoption activities. We guided concepts from initial discussion
through to concrete decisions using inclusive and collaborative processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our consultants successfully led a diverse segment of the technology industry through a
collaboration and co-design process that delivered a comprehensive framework of
policies, standards, and guidelines for eInvoicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-challenges&quot;&gt;The Challenges&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the invoicing landscape in Australia was ripe for digital disruption there were
many barriers to a successful eInvoicing framework. These barriers include: significant
commercial and competitive interests; an imbalance of power skewed against small
business; and significantly varied technology maturity across the business software
industry.
To achieve a successful outcome the initiative required the capability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translate complex technical information – to enable a level playing field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broker agreement on complex technology issues – ensuring an open and
participatory environment for all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interpret the global and domestic landscape – including several international
initiatives, each with diverse circumstances and solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-capability-wise-helped&quot;&gt;How Capability Wise Helped&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To navigate this complex ecosystem, the ATO sought specialist technology engagement support from Capability Wise.
We provided expert consultants with the following capabilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Thought Leadership&lt;/strong&gt; – to translate global technology trends into actionable options and solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-Design Experience&lt;/strong&gt; – to shape strategic technology objectives into structured consultation plans and tangible co-design outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stakeholder Needs Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; – to understand the diverse motivations and goals of the stakeholder ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forum Facilitation Skills&lt;/strong&gt; – to execute ongoing formal engagement activities in a transparent and inclusive manner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coaching and Mentoring Experience&lt;/strong&gt; – to enable other team members and industry participants to engage in the co-design and proof of concept activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our consultants quickly established a good rapport and trusted relationship with the stakeholder ecosystem based on their empathetic approach, relevant experience, and their ability to quickly produce credible results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The Capability Wise team provided an essential bridge between industry and
government, laying the foundation for what has been a highly successful
engagement between both groups.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isaac Naughton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Basware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-results&quot;&gt;The Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative has successfully proven the attractiveness and feasibility of eInvoicing in the Australian context. Several business software industry participants now have production standard eInvoicing solutions and their customers (Australian businesses) are starting to send real invoice information using the framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extensive consultation, co-design and collaboration was co-ordinated between eInvoicing participants, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1800 hours of consultation&lt;/strong&gt;, involving&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sixty organisations&lt;/strong&gt;, spread across&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five parallel working groups&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The significant outcomes of this work include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Interoperability Framework.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A fully design solution and funded project for whole of economy digital addressing infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Alpha version of the digital addressing infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Five Proof of Concept or Production Pilot Implementations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="case-study" /><category term="Digital" /><category term="Government" /><category term="Consultation" /><summary type="html">A Case Study on Successful Stakeholder Engagement in a complex technology ecosystem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Invoice Redirection Fraud: how it happens, and how to avoid it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invoice Redirection Fraud: how it happens, and how to avoid it" /><published>2020-08-16T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/insights/InvoiceFraud-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/insights/20200815-1">&lt;p&gt;As digital transformation specialists, Capability Wise understand the pitfalls businesses experience with traditional invoicing methods.  Through continuing to employ conventional billing systems organisations may be putting themselves and their suppliers at unnecessary risk, as cybercriminals become more sophisticated and attempts at fraud become more difficult to detect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of a larger cybercrime called Business Email Compromise (BEC) which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/news-alerts/business-email-compromise-scams-cost-australians-132-million&quot;&gt;cost Australians over $132 million in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, invoice redirection fraud is one of the most common strategies cybercriminals use to take advantage of businesses today.  Impersonating a business or supplier, cybercriminals access emails, intercept invoices or change bank account details in order to redirect the payment, leaving the invoice outstanding and the supplier unpaid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/blog8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the size of this problem, relevant statutory bodies and consumer watchdogs have sought to bring BEC into the spotlight, to deter scammers and educate businesses and suppliers on how to avoid falling prey to invoice redirection fraud.  For example, the ACCC have developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/&quot;&gt;ScamWatch&lt;/a&gt;, a comprehensive website that provides advice for businesses to avoid being scammed, including a checklist of issues to keep watch for in relation to fraudulent invoices. While thorough, the advice is detailed and lengthy, and it is easy to see how a time poor finance officer or small business with a variety of people paying invoices might overlook one or more of these issues, inadvertently costing their business thousands of dollars or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the increased awareness of cybercrime, organisations, both large and small continue to be fooled. In November 2019, two Sydney women were charged over their alleged involvement in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itnews.com.au/news/two-charged-over-500000-bec-scam-533833&quot;&gt;$500,000 invoice redirection scam&lt;/a&gt;, with the women who claimed to be from a Sydney-based university, requesting payment of $322,000 then $186,000 through altered invoices and fraudulent emails from an unnamed business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business email compromise scams are so lucrative, that many perpetrators continue to operate even following prosecution.  With revenue far exceeding the cost of court fines over time, cybercriminals often view these as one of the costs of doing business. One notable example is the long running &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.travelvictoria.com.au/category/scams-2/&quot;&gt;false billing scam&lt;/a&gt; in the travel and tourism industry which saw business owners receiving a renewal invoice via post or email for advertising on websites. While the advertisements did exist on the websites stated, they were never ordered or authorised by most of the business owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in 2014, after many years of the fraudulent activity, the perpetrator was fined close to $20,000 with convictions recorded. Not to be deterred, the fraudulent activity continued, and the offender was fined and convicted again in 2017 and 2019, the latter resulting in an injunction that, if breached, may end in jailtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems too, that government agencies are not immune to the sophisticated social engineering techniques employed by cybercriminals, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themandarin.com.au/68994-brisbane-450000-invoice-fraud-lesson-public-sector-scam/&quot;&gt;Brisbane City Council falling victim to a $450,000 invoice fraud scam&lt;/a&gt; in 2016.  Founded in open source intelligence gathering, it is believed the multi-tiered scam relied initially on researching current work and recently supplied services, secondly, persuading public officials to change banking details for seemingly legitimate reasons and lastly supplying a convincing invoice for payment.  It is understood that over $450,000 intended to go to a legitimate provider had been paid into a scam account, with officials only becoming aware of the scam when the service provider made contact to advise their payment had not been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons a business may fall prey to a BEC scam are varied, depending on individual circumstances.  In many instances, the scams target time-poor small to medium businesses whose staffing resources are not able to extend beyond the function of paying an invoice.  Without the capacity to investigate the integrity of each invoice received, businesses are at increased risk of being scammed.  Staff turnover, insufficient education and training and a lack of rigour around policy, processes and procedures all weaken businesses defences to the sophisticated tactics employed by cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-rounded img-responsive img-raised mb-5&quot; alt=&quot;Raised Image&quot; src=&quot;../assets/img/card-project3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the advice provided by industry experts such as ScamWatch can assist in reducing the likelihood of being impacted by a cybercrime, the best way to protect your business from invoice redirection fraud is by transitioning to e-invoicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the obvious benefits of increased efficiency, shorter pay cycles and reduced costs, e-invoicing provides the added security of enhanced compliance and prevents fraud by maintaining control through authorisations, validation and authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the growing risks businesses today face in relation to cybercrime, both organisations and suppliers need to be able to rely on the integrity of billing processes.  Transitioning to e-invoicing is the best way to build and maintain this trust, benefiting your business now and into the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="business" /><category term="Invoice" /><category term="Fraud" /><category term="e-invoicing" /><summary type="html">Business Email Compromise (BEC) cost Australians over $132 million in 2019, invoice redirection fraud is one of the most common strategies cybercriminals use to take advantage...</summary></entry></feed>